Let's start off by talking about your
job. Do you work or do you study?
>> No, I work. I work as an auditor. So, I
studied accounting and
I started as a bookkeeper and now I work
as an auditor.
>> Do you like your job?
>> Uh I do like it, but it has its uh
challenges. It's uh a very demanding job
in my opinion. So, uh
it's fun
because uh you get to learn a lot about
the company you're working with
and you get exposed to a lot of
businesses, especially if you work in uh
an accounting firm.
Uh
so, I would say that's my favorite thing
about my job. And my least favorite
could be that it's uh very demanding.
So, you work long hours. Busy season is
not easy. You need to remember why you
started to be able to continue.
Uh other than that, uh you meet a lot of
people, you make friends, uh you have a
lot of different clients. So, it's
pretty good.
>> Did you always want to be an auditor?
>> To be honest, no. I usually look at
people who know what they want to do
from day one as lucky. I wasn't one of
these people.
Uh
it only happened by chance, I would say.
I went uh into uh university. Uh
I took an accounting class, uh financial
uh accounting. I did really well. I got
the highest grade. So, when they called
me out to see like who that person was,
I was really happy about it and proud
and I decided to switch to accounting. I
didn't know what that is or what it
meant to be completely honest in
details, like what would my day-to-day
job or work look like. I did not know
unless I until I started working.
>> If you could do any other career, what
would it be?
>> So, there's a lot of things that I enjoy
doing. Two main things. The first one is
uh I love kids. So, I love working with
kids.
And the second one would be something
related to coaching and helping people
around me.
>> Now, let's talk about where you live.
Can you tell me about the kind of
accommodation you live in?
>> So, I currently live in an in an
apartment. Uh
three bedroom. It's has a big windows.
That was my most important point when I
chose the place. I have light furniture.
I like everything to be light and uh you
know, just
open. I like to wake up and see light
furniture and sun and you know, that's
what makes me happy.
>> Does your place have any amenities
around it?
>> Uh it does have, yes. It has everything.
So, we have a swimming pool, we have a
gym,
uh we have a park right in front of our
building.
Um that's what I can remember and that's
what I usually use.
>> Is there anything you would like to
change about the place where you live?
>> Yes.
So,
I know I said we have a gym, but it's
not exactly the type of gym I would
like. So, maybe some people would think
it's something minimal, but I cannot
work out without a big mirror in front
of me. I need to see how my form is. I
feel more comfortable. So,
there's no mirror. It's a bit small. So,
I would change these two things,
definitely.
>> And do you plan to live there for a long
time?
>> No, our plan is to stay there for until
the end of the year and then we'll move
to a different place.
>> Now, let's talk about animals. Do you
like animals?
>> I love animals.
I love dogs.
I like cats because I'm allergic to
them. So, since day one, I always had a
problem when
um near a cat or
I see one. Uh I love all types of
animals. I love elephants,
um giraffes,
cows,
monkeys, all of them.
>> [laughter]
>> But, my favorite I love dogs. They're my
number one.
>> Did you have a pet when you were a
child? Just jumping in to give you our
free gift. We analyzed hundreds of band
789 speaking performances and we
analyzed the vocabulary. [music] We've
put all the best words, phrases, idioms
into one PDF for you. If you would like
that, go to the description, click on
the link. It's our gift to you. You can
download it 100% for free.
>> No, I only
Yes, I had
What was it called? It's a type of bird.
I forgot the exact name of the type of
the bird of bird, but yes, I had a bird
and I had fish at some point.
They're not really
You can't really play with them, but I
had two at some point.
>> Now, let's talk about friends. Can you
describe your best friend?
>> Uh my best friend. Yes, of course. So,
uh we've been friends for I don't know
how many years now, so
maybe 15 years or more.
Uh
She's a She's a very loyal friend. She's
a loyal uh
very nice, kind, thoughtful.
She's always been there for me.
Whenever I needed her with the honest
opinion, whether it's good or bad.
Loyal, number one.
>> What type of people do you most commonly
make friends with? What are their their
traits, their character traits?
>> So, for me, I I really look for kindness
in people. Uh they have to be kind,
loyal,
uh they don't lie. Um Real friends,
they're there when you need them.
They're there in good times and in bad
times before good times.
Uh and you only
uh you only discover this
with time. And with the events and, you
know, so that's how I decide that this
person is a person that I want to be
close to. So, I'm going to talk about an
app called TikTok, which most of people
know now.
Uh and I decided to stop using it. First
time I used it was uh a few years ago
when it came out. At the beginning,
everyone was really
uh happy with it. Uh I started using it
because uh I remember I used to look for
recipes, for inspirations, if I have a a
dinner with my friends, if I have a
whatever, a party,
I see what I can wear, I take
inspirations, where to go buy my
clothes, outfits. Even if I'm hosting,
let's say I'm having friends over for
brunch, lunch, dinner. I just see how I
can decorate the the table
or ideas of what I can cook and stuff
like that. Um it honestly helped me with
a lot of things like preparing for an
interview, let's say, or even
how to act in a certain situation.
Sometimes a lot of people go through
situations that you go through and
you'll be surprised how much advice you
can find on TikTok. I'm not saying it's
the best, but you can find some good
advice. The reason I stopped using it
was because at some point
uh
I realized that my attention span a span
was getting so bad, I couldn't focus, I
couldn't
watch a a full movie, let's say, or a
full video without pressing times two. I
couldn't just wait. I wanted everything
very quickly and I read about it. I
realized that one of the reasons could
be me using social media, especially
TikTok, because of the
short videos, quick videos that we see.
I scroll all all day and more than that
uh I realized that
the second I open the app when I close
it, I see that two, three hours have
passed. So, I realized it's just a waste
of time.
>> We've been talking about technology and
we're going to continue to talk about
computer games and technology in
education. Are computer games popular in
your country?
>> I believe they are because I hear a lot
of people talking about them, but
I'm not related to any type of like I'm
not interested or I don't play any
computer games. I don't know anything
about them.
>> Let's talk about technology in the
classroom. Can technology be helpful in
the classroom?
>> I graduated a few years ago.
So, I we didn't have that much
technology
uh like these days, but maybe I can tell
you about how I use technology in my own
job. So, for example, it does really
help. I'm going to give you an example.
If I have a meeting, let's say, and I
need to take notes with AI or just
a certain app, I can record the meeting,
it summarizes it to me, it gives me the
main points, the important points,
what we focused on.
Anything I ask it to do, it does. So,
that instead of taking me like 7 hours
to do it or not going to maybe 2 hours
to do, would take me 15 minutes.
>> Do you think that students know more
about AI than most teachers?
>> Of course.
Of course, 100%. The younger generation
grew up
with AI being normal, so they know so
much about it. For maybe older
generation, they have to acquire the
knowledge or learn about it or put more
effort. It's not something that they're
used to, unlike
younger generation where it's no normal.
So, I think in my opinion, yeah, they do
know more than
their teachers.
>> Do you think that AI will ever replace
teachers in the classroom?
>> I think so, yes.
For now, I see it's doing a lot of
things. It's just surprising. It's
it's scary, too.
Yeah, I believe it it can replace
70% of the jobs,
if not more.
>> Can you think of a specific application
or a specific thing that AI could do to
help students in the classroom?
>> A specific app?
>> Or a specific app application, not app
as in a app in the App Store, but a
specific
methodology or something it could do to
help students. So, for example, you
talked about uh in your job the
application is note-taking for meetings.
What could AI do in the classroom?
>> Exactly same thing. They also need to
take a lot of notes. So, for example,
for me, I used to like listening to the
teacher more than just taking notes and
being in a rush and you know, because I
like to focus and just understand what
the teacher is saying. So, if I had this
before, this would have helped me a lot
because I focus with the teacher and
then I go back home, I reread what he
said or she said. I understand it more.
I have it written clearly. So, I would
have used it that way.
Maybe there's more and I don't know
about like what they use it for, but
this would be something important to me
and useful.
>> So, what I'm going to do is go through
each part, give you some feedback, and
then we'll talk about your scores.
If you would like your speaking assessed
one-on-one, we do offer that as part of
our VIP package. To thank you for
watching the video, I'll offer you 10%
off. All you have to do is just go to
the description, click the link, and you
can get 10% off today. Part one was
excellent. Um
you The only thing was you forgot the
name of the bird.
And [laughter] but you dealt with that
really well because you talked through
it. So, you didn't just say like, "Mhm,
what is the name of the" Like some
people will be like, "Mhm, uh uh uh"
and they'll think about it for a very
long time. You just were like, "I can't
think of it" and then you moved on. So,
it felt like a conversation. It didn't
feel like a test. It didn't feel like I
was interrogating you and trying to pull
the English out of you. It was just like
a normal conversation. So, it was it was
really good. Your development was good.
I wouldn't change anything. I wouldn't
give you any advice about part one
because you did really well. Part two,
you did something that I would be a
little bit worried about. What you did
was you listed nearly everything that's
ever on TikTok. You were like, "You
could try it. You could do this and you
could do this and you could do this. You
stop that after a while, and then you
moved on to why you decided to
um stop doing it. The question was about
why you decided to stop doing it. So, if
you just kept listing lots of things,
this is a very common thing that we see
is students will get on to one topic,
and they'll just list everything. So,
for example, you ask them about food,
"What's your favorite food?" "I like
Thai. I like Italian. I like Lebanese. I
like uh Arabic food. I like pizza. I
like And they don't they don't realize
they're doing it. You did it a little
bit, but then you switched. I think it's
like a a little bit of a safety blanket
where people it's easy to list stuff,
and but listing a bunch of things
doesn't allow you to really show the
examiner the range of grammar, the range
of vocabulary that you have because
you're not really speaking in complete
sentences. You're just creating a a
little shopping list of of words. So,
it's fine to do that a little bit, but
be careful about that. I don't think
it's a huge problem for you, and but I
just want to bring it up
out of an abundance of caution.
Um
you but you once you moved on to that,
you did really, really well. Part three,
there were a couple of of topics where
you didn't know about them, and I really
like that you said that you didn't know
anything about it. So, computer games um
is not a universal thing. Not everyone
is into computer games. Not everybody
plays computer games. But you you're
aware of what they are, and you just
started talking about it, and then said
like, "To be honest, I'm not I don't
really know anything about them. I'm not
really into computer games." You have
demonstrated to the examiner that A, you
don't know anything about computer
games, but B, you can talk about why you
don't know anything about them. And a
good examiner will not keep asking you
about that topic if you've made it clear
that you don't have a lot of knowledge
about it. So, they want to give give
best opportunity to show how great your
English is.
Peppering you with question after
question about a topic you don't really
know much about is not going to help you
do that. So, you notice that after you
said that, I switched to a different
topic and we started talking about
technology in the classroom. One thing
that you did as well, I asked you about
technology in the classroom and then you
switched it to "Well, I don't know about
that, but this is how I use it in my
job." I think that is absolutely fine,
but make sure that you bring it back to
the question. So, you said, "In my job,
we use AI for meetings." You could have
then took it back to and said, "And
that's how teachers could use it with
their students." So, instead of them
writing notes furiously, they could
listen to the the teacher, let the AI
record, and then look back at the notes
after class and they can learn from
them. So, always bring it back to the
question because part of your mark is
did you answer the question? Did you
remain
talking about that topic or answering
the question throughout your answer? You
also, I was asking you about like, will
um AI replace teachers? Like, that's not
certain right now. It's a quite a
difficult question, but you did
speculate about it like it they might
use it for this. And then you related it
to something you know about, which was
really really good. If possible, I would
try and add a little bit more detail in
part three. A little bit um you could
use examples, explanations. Why do some
people think this? Why do other people
think that? Or it could be a personal
story like you did using AI in meetings
and things like that.
It it is not a problem here. Again, I'm
trying to think of
if you did you haven't done the real
test in a long time. Um if you were to
do it again, is there anything that when
you're under pressure, you might do too
much of you might make a mistake because
of you're just stressed.
Um you might give very short answers and
not give more detail, not give examples.
You could talk about irrelevant things.
So, I'm just helping you. What you did
was fine, but I'm just trying to help
you out as much as much as possible.
>> think it's amazing. And I really I'm I
am going to use this feedback even for
my life. When someone asks me a
question, it's always good to think
about the question when you're
answering, you know, because sometimes
you take the question, you start
answering, you change directions. So,
it's even good for me to
>> So, good way to think about it is
think about the question, directly
answer it right away.
So, here's what I think or here's what
other people think because not you don't
agree with every viewpoint. Something
like should AI be used in the classroom?
Some people think yeah, it should be
used way more than it is. Another people
are like no, it can't replace humans.
So, you could but try and say like I
think this. Here's why I think this.
Here's an example So, I think that AI
should be used for note-taking. I think
it's really useful because students can
review their notes after and they can
focus on the lesson instead of taking
notes during that. An example of this is
the app Otter AI or something. Whatever
whatever app you can you can think of.
I've used it before and I
>> about me. I have like I don't remember.
>> [laughter]
>> So, for the app yesterday I used it for
my job and I forgot the name of the of
the website I used for a meeting
actually.
>> use the exact name. It's not a knowledge
of AI apps test. Don't worry about that.
Um you can say but other people think
that you know, AI has no place in the
classroom and you know, it it's really
important for students to develop the
the skill of note-taking themselves
because that's something that they will
have to do in the future. Personally, I
don't think that they will use a have to
make notes in the future because AI will
take that over completely. So, my
opinion is you know, that that we should
use more of it for that purpose.
Something like that. Let's talk about
your scores. You will get 25% for
fluency and coherence. That means did
you speak at an appropriate speed
without unnatural pausing and did you
answer the question? Pronunciation, can
I understand you? Grammar, vocabulary.
Your fluency and coherence is excellent.
Um, you don't speak too fast or you
don't speak too slow. Fluency isn't
really about speed, it's more about how
smoothly you you you speak. It's the
smoothness of your speech. Um, so
without unnatural pausing and and you do
that sometimes, but it's all only just
to think of the next idea. You do it
very infrequently, which is excellent.
You always answer the question.
Sometimes you do start talking about
something a little bit irrelevant, um,
but it is rare. You do develop all your
answers. Sometimes it could be a little
bit more developed, but again, it's not
a huge problem. Um, so you would be at
the very top for level, which is about
nine for fluency and coherence.
Pronunciation, I can understand every
single word you say. You are not a
native English speaker, and uh, you grew
up speaking Arabic, so it is amazing
that your pronunciation is as clear and
as easy to understand as it is. Not only
that, you have very good use of
intonation. Um, so your your voice is
going up and down to convey meaning very
accurately and very natural, um,
word stress and sentence stress. You're
stressing certain words to convey
meaning, and you do that like a native
speaker would do that, which is very
difficult for Arabic speakers because
the rhythm of Arabic is very different
from the rhythm of English. So you're
doing very very well there. Vocabulary
is very accurate. You're never
using words that just have the wrong
meaning, or you're never trying to use
words that, um, are inappropriate.
You're very very accurate. For example,
when you're talking about Tik Tok and
not using it, you're talk using words
like attention span and I couldn't focus
and I was, um pressing
uh 2x and I scrolled all day and two two
or three hours have passed. It's just a
complete waste of time. So, none of
these words are particularly advanced.
None of these phrases are like the most
advanced English in the world, but they
are very topic specific. So, you don't
talk about attention span when you're
talking about wearing hats or baking
cakes or the weather. You talk about
attention span and losing focus and
scrolling and hours have passed and a
waste of time when you're talking about
TikTok and Instagram and things like
that. So, any topic that I threw at you,
you have very appropriate and accurate
vocabulary to talk about that. It
doesn't matter what topic I give you.
Some people might say that you need to
expand your vocabulary a little bit. I
don't think that you do. I think if you
try to start inserting really advanced
vocabulary for the sake of it, then it
you [clears throat] will it'll lead to
you making more mistakes. I think it's
absolutely fine. And grammar, there's
tiny little slips from time to time. For
example, you said which most of people
know instead of which most people know.
If you say which most of people know, I
know exactly what that means. It doesn't
stop me understanding what you're saying
and it wasn't like you had um that error
over and over and over again. You don't
like it's not like every preposition or
article usage is has has an issue. It's
extremely rare for you to make a a
mistake and it's just a little slip and
that's how native English speakers
speak. When you're speaking Arabic, I'm
sure you make little slips from time to
time. Everybody does. When I'm speaking
English, I make little slips to get a
band nine. You don't need to be perfect
and maybe you made more mistakes. I
don't know. I didn't pick up on them.
Um but that was the only one I picked up
on. So, you would get a perfect band
nine for everything. So, you are at an
extremely high level and that is
extremely rare for someone who didn't
grow up in a native English-speaking
country. So, you should be very proud of
your English-speaking ability and and uh
yeah, well done.